Finding Aid for the Miriam Matthews collection of Los Angeles Newspapers on African Americans, ca. 1948-1985
UCLA Library Special Collections
Miriam Matthews collection of Los Angeles Newspapers on African Americans
ca. 1948-1985
1839
Matthews, Miriam, collector.
42 oversize flat boxes (16.5 linear ft.)
Collection consists of newspapers collected by Miriam Matthews, mostly published for the African American community in Los Angeles and concerning African American topics. Titles include the California Eagle (1958-1959), Los Angeles Sentinel (1955-1985) and the Los Angeles Tribune (1958) as well as some clippings and pages of other newspapers from the Los Angeles area.
University of California, Los Angeles. Library Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles Matthews, 2009.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 6940331
Biography/History
Miriam Matthews was born on August 6, 1905 in Pensacola, Florida and moved to Los Angeles with her family two years later. After graduating from Los Angeles High School in 1922, Matthews studied at the University of California, Southern Branch (now UCLA) for two years. She transferred to the University of California, Berkeley where she graduated with a B.A. in 1926 and a certificate in librarianship in 1927, becoming the first known certified African American librarian in California. Matthews began her career at the Los Angeles Public Library (LAPL) in 1927 and became a branch librarian in 1934. She took two leaves of absence from LAPL, one in 1940 to work at the New York Public Library in a librarian exchange program and another from 1944 to 1945 in order to earn a master's degree in library science from the University of Chicago. In 1949, she was promoted to regional librarian, a position she held until her retirement from LAPL in 1960. Matthews was one of the first people to advocate for the establishment of Negro History Week (now African American History Month) in Los Angeles, leading to its official observance by the City of Los Angeles in 1931. In 1946, she became chairman of the California Library Association Committee on Intellectual Freedom. The following year, she was appointed to the American Library Association Committee on Intellectual Freedom (1947-1951) where she contributed to the 1948 revision of the Library Bill of Rights. In 1977, Gov. Edmund Brown appointed Matthews to the California Heritage Preservation Commission and California State Historic Records Advisory Board. She contributed to the establishment of an archives and records management program for the City of Los Angeles in 1979. While a member of the Los Angeles 200 Committee in 1981, Matthews proposed and implemented the construction of a historical plaque detailing the names, ages, and races of the city founders. Matthews died on Mercer Island, Washington on June 23, 2003. In 2003, the Los Angeles Historical Society established the annual Miriam Matthews Award in her honor. The Los Angeles Public Library Hyde Park branch was renamed for her in 2004.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of newspapers collected by Miriam Matthews, mostly published for the African American community in Los Angeles and concerning African American topics. Titles include the California Eagle (1958-1959), Los Angeles Sentinel (1955-1985) and the Los Angeles Tribune (1958) as well as some clippings and pages of other newspapers from the Los Angeles area.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Newspaper publication titles
Dates of publication
Loose clippings
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Matthews, Miriam --Archives.; African American women librarians --California --Los Angeles --Archival resources.
Genres and Forms of Material
Newspapers.
Related Material
Miriam Matthews Papers (Collection 1804). Available at Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Miriam Matthews Collection. African American Museum and Library at Oakland (AAMLO).
Miriam Matthews Photographic Collection. California African American Museum, Los Angeles.
Container List
- L.A. Sentinel. Volumes: XXI; XXIV; XXVI; XXVII; XXVIII, Oct. 13, 1955 - Dec. 28, 1961.; 19 items.
  Issues: No.42, No. 20, No.31, No.n/a; No.23, No. 27, No. 29, No.32, No. 35, No. 47, No. 49, No. 50, No. 51, No. 42, No. 44, No. 45, No. 50, No. 51, No. 1
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXI, Issue: No. 42, Oct. 13, 1955.; 32 pages, 10 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: 5000 Jam Till Death Protest Rally Local Atty. Named to State Board
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIV, Issue: No. 20, May 8, 1958.; 36 pages, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Jail "Dad" In Baby Death Probe
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIV, Issue: No. 31, July 24, 1958.; 36 pages, 15 cents. (Box 1)
    Headline: 5 Killed in 30-Ft. Auto Plunge
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: No. 50, Dec. 1, 1960.; 48 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Arrest 25 for Numbers Racket
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: No. 51, Dec. 8, 1960.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Citizens Demand Vice Cleanup + Students Swingled in $300,000 Book Racket
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: No. 49, Nov. 24, 1960.; 36 pages, 2 sections, 15 cents
    Headline: Fresno Conference Inspires Negro Leaders + Schools Mark Time in New Oreleans Dispute
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: No. 47, Nov. 10, 1960.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Big Negro Vote Elects Kennedy + Gunman Robs Watts Bank
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: No. 35, Aug. 18, 1960.; 40 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Mate Slays 'Unfaithful' Wife
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: No. 29, July 7, 1960.; 40 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents
    Headline: Strangler eludes Police Block
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: No. 27, June 23, 1960.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Police Slay Boy, 16 in Stolen Car Chase
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: N/A, Mar. 10, 1960.; 40 pages; 2 sections (torn front cover) (Box 1)
    Headline: Ben Waller Targetߪ
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: No. 23, May 26, 1960.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Three Tots Perish in Blaze
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVI, Issue: No. 32, July 28, 1960.; 40 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Police Capture Sex-Slayer, 19
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 45, Nov. 2, 1961.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Beautician Murders Wide and Her Lover +White Realtor Cut Over Negro Listing
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 42, Oct. 12, 1961.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: 10th Recall Drive Set + Mystery Rider Guns MTA Teenage Bandit
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 50, Dec. 7, 1961.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Real Estate Broker Slays Sweetie, Self + Greathound Taking Driver Applications
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 44, Oct. 26, 1961.; 48 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Flames Peril 6, 3 Tots Perish + Teenagers, Police Clash in Compton
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 51, Dec. 14, 1961.; 48 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Teen Gang Killing Laid to 'Gladiators'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVIII, Issue: No. 1, Dec. 28, 1961.; 32 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 1)
    Headline: Weaver Slated for Cabinet
- L.A. Sentinel. Volumes: XVII; XVIII, Feb. 15, 1962 - Dec. 20, 1962.; 14 items.
  Issues: No. 8, No. 9, No. 11, No. 15, No. 35, No. 39, No.40, No. 41, No. 43, No. 45, No. 46, No. 47, No.50, No.51
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 45, Nov. 8, 1962.; 48 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Minority Vote Proves Winning Margin for Brown + Hawkins Our First in Congress
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 51, Dec. 20, 1962.; 40 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Dorothy Dandridge Charges Hubby Hocked Her Belongings
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 50, Dec. 13, 1962.; 44 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Showdown Near in Battle for NAACP Prexy + Showmen Trapped in Clerk's Slaying
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 47, Nov. 22, 1962.; 36 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Community Unites in Lindsay-for-Council Drive + Bank Bandits Trapped After Blazing Gun Fight
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 46, Nov. 15, 1962.; 48 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Woman Dies at Church as Worship Continues + Consider Gilbert Lindsay Major Choice for Council
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 41, Oct. 4, 1962.; 48 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Uncertain Calm at Ole Miss as World Blasts Dixie Bias
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 35, Aug. 23, 1962.; 48 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Stepmother Fatally Beats Boy with Rod + JFk Hawkins Talk
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 15, Apr. 5, 1962.; 52 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: L.A. Dodgers Chavez Ravine Dream Come True + Girl, 13, Heroine in South L.A. Robbery
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 11, Mar. 8, 1962.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Montrey Highlands Pickets Protest Realty Bias + Find Woman's Body in' Love Nest'
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 9, Feb. 22, 1962.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Mate Boasts About Love Affairs, Slain by Wife + Urban Department Doomed
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 8, Feb. 15, 1962.; 44 pages,;4 sections,15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Beautician Slain at Bus Stop + Jon Arnett Denies Real Estate Bias Deal
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVIII, Issue: No. 43, Oct. 25, 1962.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Brown Stresses Civil Rights
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVIII, Issue: No. 39, Sep. 20, 1962.; 44 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Integration at Baldwin School + jury Clears Manager in Motel Lot Slaying
  - L.A Sentinel. Volume: XXVIII, Issue: No. 40, Sep. 27, 1962.; 44 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 2)
    Headline: Nation Demands Firm Action By U.S. in Mississippi Rebellion
- L.A. Sentinel. Volumes: XXVII; XXVIII; XXIX, Jan. 17, 1963 - Sep. 12, 1963.; 18 items.
  Issues: No. 3, No. 4, No. 6, No. 7, No. 9, No. 13, No. N/A, No. N/A, No. 17, No. 20, No. 21, No. 24, No. 25, No. 29, No. 30, No. 35, No. 36
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: N/A, Issue: N/A, Apr. 4, 1963.; Section B only; Compton-South L.A. section (Box 3)
    Headline: 'Cadillac Bandits' Nabbed
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: N/A, Issue: N/A, Apr. 18, 1963.; Section C only; Compton-South L.A section (Box 3)
    Headline: Kids Turn Compton Into 'Shoot-Out'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 25, June 27, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Dad Held in Fiery Death of 4 Tots
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 35, Sep. 5, 1963.; 48 pagese; 2 sections, 15 cents
    Headline: 'I Loved Him,' Girl Asserts in Ray Charles Paternity Case
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 34, Aug. 29, 1963.; 56 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: 200,000 March for Freedom and Jobs
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 30, Aug. 1, 1963.; 56 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Act Now on Rights-Reuther + Gun-Play Jails Gospel Singer
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 29, July 25, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Disabled Vet Held in Party Killing
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 36, Sep. 12, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: 'I Had to Destroy Them' Slayer of Wife, Two Children Asserts
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 13, Mar. 28, 1963.; 56 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Rape Victim Recalls 'I Was All Shook Up!' + Lindsay, Bradley in Hot Races
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 21, May 23, 1963.; 54 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Dr. King to Get Hero's Welcome Here Sunday + Church Backs up Chambers Jr.
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 4, Jan. 24, 1963.; 44 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Couple Rescues Vice Cop in Vicious Street Attack
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 3, Jan. 17, 1963.; 48 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Pretty D-J Sues Bass For Party 'Assault'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 7, Feb. 14, 1963.; 48 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Problems of Jobless Railroad Workers Exposed + Student's Slaying Stuns City
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 6, Feb. 7, 1963.; 48 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Solons Urge JFK to Name Shaw P.O. Chief
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVII, Issue: No. 24, June 20, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Kennedy Urges Firm Rights Laws
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVIII, Issue: No. 20, May 16, 1963.; 53 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Birmingham Still a 'Powder Keg'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVIII, Issue: No. 17, Apr. 25, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Mayor Calls for Prayer Day on Dixie Injustices 'Don't Run Over That Girl Again'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXVIII, Issue: No. 9, Feb. 28, 1963.; 44 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 3)
    Headline: Schoolmarm Shoots Father of 3
- L.A. Sentinel. Volumes: XXIX, Sep. 19, 1963 - Dec. 26, 1963.; 14 items.
  Issues: No. 37, No. 38, No. 39, No. 40, No. 41, No. 42, No. 43, No.45, No. 46, No. 47, No. 48, No. 49, No. 50, No. 51
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 42, Oct. 24, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Infant Dies in South L.A. Fire
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 37, Sep. 19, 1963.; 52 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Vile Church Bombing 'Atrocity of Century'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 38, Sep. 26, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: 'Cool Bandit' Makes $5000 Haul
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 39, Oct. 3, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: 'Hands Stomped, Copts Beat Me' + Rights Unit Given Year
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 49, Dec. 12, 1963.; 56 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Brown Hits Housing Initiative + Charges Chief Left Her Injured on Highway 99
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 41, Oct. 17, 1963.; 52 pages, 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Foul Play Ruled Out Fall Fatal to Minister
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 50, Dec. 19, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: The Inside Story of Queen Dinah Washingston's Death
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 48, Dec. 5, 1963.; 56 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Chambers Jr. Given Probation + Man Grieves Self to Death Over JFK
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 47, Nov. 28, 1963.; 40 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Like Being 'Orphaned' Minorities Mourn Kennedy
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 46, Nov. 21, 1963.; 56 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Gov. Brown to Fight Housing Initiative
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 45, Nov. 14, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Charged with Pandering Chambers Jr. Changes Plea to 'Not Guilty'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 43, Oct. 31, 1963.; 56 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: 'I only Wanted a Fix' Guns Roar: Pawnbroker Shot
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 40, Oct. 10, 1963.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Chambers Jr. Admits Guilt
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXIX, Issue: No. 51, Dec. 26, 1963.; 32 pages; 2 sections, 15 cents (Box 4)
    Headline: Mother, 3 Children Die From Gas Fumes in Pre-Yule Tragedy
- L.A. Sentinel. Volumes: XXX, Jan. 7, 1964 - Nov. 12, 1964.; 12 items.
  Issues: No. 1, No. 3, No. 4, No. 16, No. 32, No. 35, No. 36, No. 44, No. 45
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: N/A, Issue: N/A, Jan. 7, 1964.; Incomplete: Feature section only (Box 5)
    Headline: Negroes Pace '65 Rose Parade
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 16, Apr. 23, 1964.; 144 pages; 8 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: Baptists Condemn Stall-ins + Blast Housing Initiative
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 33, Aug. 20, 1964.; 62 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: Mexicans Qualify 'No Stand' on Proposition 14
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 45, Nov. 12, 1964.; 62 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: Youth Shot - Police Thwart Gang War
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 44, Nov. 5, 1964.; 60 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: Mighty Minority Vote Sparks LBJ Victory
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 36, Sep. 10, 1964.; 56 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: Police Kill 1 in 2 Gun Fights
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 35, Sep. 3, 1964.; 62 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: 'Penny Ante' Killer Slays Two
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 16, Apr. 23, 1964.; The Sentinel's 30th Anniversary Progess Edition - 144 pages; 8 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: The Life Story of Sidney Poitier
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 4, Jan. 30, 1964.; 56 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: Tot, 5, Trapped in Home Fire + Map Mass Voter Drive
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 3, Jan. 23, 1964.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: Charles Loses Paternity Suit
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 1, Jan. 9, 1964.; 52 pages; 3 sections, 15 cents
    Headline: Teacher Slain Over Sandwich + President Hits Race Bias
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXX, Issue: No. 32, Aug. 13, 1964.; 60 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 5)
    Headline: Exclusive - Champion Cassius Clay Takes a Bride!
- L.A. Sentinel. Volumes: XXXI; XXI, Aug. 12, 1965 - July 14, 1966.; 16 items.
  Issues: No. 32, No.36, No.47, No.49, No.50, No.51, No.14, No.39, No.17, No.18, No.20, No.21, No.22, No.24, No.25, No.27, No.28
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXI, Issue: No. 27, July 7, 1966.; 48 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: NAACP Boots Nazi, Shuns 'Black Power'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 18, May 5, 1966.; 56 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Korean Bride of Ex-GI Found Slain
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 50, Dec. 16, 1965.; 66 pages; 6 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Twenty Thousand View Watts Yule Spectacle + Car Trunk Bares Body
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 25, June 23, 1966.; 54 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Welder Reveals $10,000 Offer to Slay Martin Luther King
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 24, June 16, 1966.; 56 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Dymally's Wide Sues for Divorce
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 22, June 2, 1966.; 60 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Mrs. Deadwyler To Ask City for 'Six Figures' in Lawsuit
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 21, May 26, 1966.; 56 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: 'Car Didn't Move'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 28, July 14, 1966.; 56 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Adoption of Eight-Year-Old Negro Boy Spurs Racial Terrorism in Glendale + 'Black Power' Split Widens
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 20, May 19, 1966.; 58 pages-; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Hundreds in Killin Protest South L.A. Violence Renewed
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 39, Sep. 29, 1966.; 48 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Riot Creates Tensions in Troubled Bay Area
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 51, Dec. 23, 1965.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: 2 Women Quizzed in 'Love Slayings'
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 49, Dec. 9, 1965.; 64 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Throngs Await SLA Christmas Parade Saturday + Riot Report Debated
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 47, Nov. 25, 1965.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Central, Watts Rebuilding OK'd
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 36, Sep. 9, 1965.; 54 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Dot Dandridge is Dead
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 32, Aug. 12, 1965.; 60 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Angelesnos Greet Convention Delegates
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 14, Apr. 21, 1966.; 60 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents
    Headline: Mt. Sinai Defaults Church Foreclosed
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 17, Apr. 28, 1966.; 62 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 6)
    Headline: Hawkins Brothers Clash in Eyoa War
- L.A. Sentinel. Volumes: XXXI, Aug. 25, 1966 - Dec. 29, 1966.; 16 items.
  Issues: No. 30, No. 31, No. 32, No. 33, No. 34, No. 37, No. 38, No. 40, No. 43, No. 44, No. 45, No. 45, No. 49, No. 50, No. 51, No. 52
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 51, Dec. 22, 1966.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Mahalia Seeks Divorce + Negro Editors Buys Into Pro Football Club
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 44, Nov. 3, 1966.; 52 pages, 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Brown Winner in Poll + 'Biased' Cop Faces $300,000 Lawsuit
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 45, Nov. 10, 1966.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Carwasher Mum on 'Marriage' to Nurse
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 46, Nov. 17, 1966.; 48 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Is Wills-O'Malley Feud a Hoax + Nude's Death Puzzles
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 43, Oct. 27, 1966.; 52 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Wife Clears Lomax + Gil Lindsay Blasted for His Stand on Flouridation
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 50, Dec. 15, 1966.; 48 pages; 6 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Central Avenue Face-Lift + The Hot 'Chitlin' Murder
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 33, Aug. 18, 1966.; 52 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Santa Ana Bias in Realty Bared
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 49, Dec. 8, 1966.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Sam Cooke is Gone, but Legend Lives on + Free Postman's Murder Suspect
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 40, Oct. 6, 1966.; 50 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: U.S. Sleuths Probing Slain Postman's Loan Operations
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 38, Sep. 22, 1966.; 44 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: KKK's Secret Known: Major Rally a Flop
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 34, Aug. 26, 1966.; 48 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Freeway Suicide + Yorty's Watts Testimony Draws Senators' Rebuke
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 32, Aug. 11, 1966.; 60 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Fitting Last Rites Set for Rep. Hawkins Wife
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 31, Aug. 4, 1966.; 56 pages; 5 sections. 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: Who Shot Nitery Czar?
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 30, July 28, 1966.; 56 pages; 5 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)
    Headline: $300,000,000 Deadwyler Claim Biggest in Community History
  - L.A. Sentinel. Volume: XXXI, Issue: No. 52, Dec. 29, 1966.; 36 pages; 4 sections, 15 cents (Box 7)